I had a stipend of 250
у меня была стипендия 250
hryvnia What do you think is normal Well, the
гривен Как вы считаете это нормальная ну
amount of the stipend was 30 dollars It's
сумма стипендия- это было 30 долларов
cool And how much is the
получается Прикольно А сколько сейчас
stipend in Russia now I don't know I Yes, yes,
стипендия в России я не знаю я А да-да
yes How much is the stipend in
да Сколько сколько сейчас стипендия в
Russia now The stipend in Russia is 2,000
России сейчас стипендия в России 2.000
rubles It's 20 dollars less than it was in Ukraine
руб Это 20 долларов меньше чем в Украине
Hello Hello I'm from the city of
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте Я из города
Khmelnitsky Where are you from the city of Saki
Хмельницкий Вы откуда город Саки Очень
Nice to meet you Cool And how do you communicate, Yuri
приятно Прикольно А чём общаетесь юрий
Me Andrey
Меня Андрей
And Andrey about everything I'm such an
А Андрей обо всём подряд Я такой
open
открытый
person I can talk about everything You are
человек могу обо всём пообщаться Вы
some kind of low-level official no I am
какой-то чиновник мелкого звена нет я А
No, I'm a hotel administrator
нет я администратор гостиницы
Cool How is the holiday season in
Прикольно Как сейчас курортный сезон в
Saki now
Саках
And I'll turn off the exercise machine from the headphones And
А я сключу тренажёлочок от наушников
yes, just turn on the light Yes, I
заработал А да только свет включите Да я
have a flashlight No problem Please please Yes,
с фонариком Без проблем Пожалуйста
everything is super great There are reservations,
пожалуйста А да всё супер отлично
people are traveling There is amazut
Брони есть люди едут Амазут есть
We don't have it on the beach
У нас на пляже нет
And nearby in Evpatoria
А рядом в Евпатории
And closer, well, in Sevastopol I know they found it
а ближе ну в Севастополе я знаю находили
In Evpatoria they found it
в Евпатории находили
Well  something like that
Ну как-то так
Got it Yeah How much does a hotel cost now in
Понял Угу Сколько сейчас стоит отель в
stacks
стаках
Well, we have a middle-class hotel
ну у нас э такого среднего класса отель
for the winter
на зимний
period, basically, it's now completely
период в основном сейчас совершенно
inexpensive 2,000 rubles per day This is a two-
недорого 2.000 руб в сутки Это двух
bed room And closer to the season, the price
двухместный номер А ближе к сезону цена
will already increase depending on the
уже будет повышаться в зависимости от
month The start is from 6,000 Stop stop stop
месяца Старт идёт от 6.000 Стоп стоп
2,000 rubles per day Yes, that's 20
стоп 2.000 руб в сутки да это 20
dollars
долларов
Yes
Да
And what's included in the expensive
А что входит за дорого
What's included there What's included in the price of
что в Что входит туда что входит в цену
hotel accommodation And the gym is
проживание в отеле А тренажёрный зал
free and free for our guests Well,
бесплат бесплатный для наших гостей Ну
hotel accommodation What does this
проживание в отеле Что это имеется в
mean What are the parameters of the room
виду какой параметры номера
And a suite
а люкс
For 20 dollars a suite Yes And what's included in this suite
За 20 долларов люкс Да А что в этот люкс
aa a full set of towels Can you really
аа полный набор полотенец
imagine how cool it is
Неужели чайник представляете прикольно
Unexpectedly So what else yes And a kettle Wi-Fi
Неожиданно Так что ещё да А чайник Wi-Fi
TV
телевизор
Wait, do you have non-suite rooms
Подождите а у вас есть номера не люкс
They are without Wi-Fi Yes,
они без вай-фая да
no, we only have suite rooms And so what
нет у нас только люкс номера А так что
goes kettle Wi-Fi TV
ходит чайник Wi-Fi телевизор
You can go to the site and by the way
Вы можете зайти на сайт и кстати
see all this Oh, tell me the site I'll
посмотреть это всё О скажите сайт я
look now And although no, I'm looking at
сейчас посмотрю А хотя нет я смотрю на
your flag, I probably won't tell you
ваш флаг наверное не буду я вам говорить
Scary Got it Okay ok Then tell me
Стрёмно Понял О'кей хорошо То расскажите
what is included in a
что входит в номер
double room Right now, just a second And that's it,
двухспальну Сейчас секунду секунду А всё
he walked by Double
он прошёл Двухспальная
bed bed
кровать постельное
linen
бельё
safe air conditioning TV dishes
сейф кондиционер телевизор посуда
Disposable toothbrush toothpaste
Зубная щётка одноразовая зубная паста
disposable shampoo shower gel
одноразовая шампунь гель для
soap Well, yeah, that's basically it Breakfast is
мыло Ну да и всё в принципе Завтрак
included
входит
but not in winter,
а в зимний период нет летом шведский
buffet in summer
стол
Where do people
А где люди
eat in the morning
едят утром
and a cafe And there's a cafe Yes Yes We have a
а кафе А есть кафешка Да Да У нас в
gym in our hotel Finnish sauna
отеле тренажёрный зал финская сауна
billiards table tennis
бильярд настольный теннис
cafe swimming pool
кафе бассейн
Cool Well, that's
Прикольно
it And how many rooms do
Ну такое А сколько номеров
we have three buildings at the moment
у нас три корпуса на данный момент В
Each building has 12 rooms As many
каждом корпусе по 12 номеров
as three buildings with 12 rooms 36
Прямо аж три корпуса по 12 номеров 36
rooms
номеров
Yes, it's some kind of mini-hotel
Да это какой-то миниотельчик
Yes, it's small Very small
Да небольшой Совершенно небольшой
Got it That's clear 300 m from 300 m from the beach
Понял То понятно 300 м от 300 м от пляжа
And what is the current occupancy rate
И сколько сейчас заселённость
now I'll
сейчас
say 24% A
скажу 24%
quarter yes,
Четверть
that is, out of three, six, nine rooms,
да то есть из тришести девять номеров
eight even
восемь даже
Yes, that's
Да
cool And how many service
прикольно А сколько обслуживающего
personnel do you have
персонала у вас
six
шесть
administrators Six administrators
администраторов Шесть администраторов
Two cooks Two  waiter Already 10
Два повара Два официанта Уже 10
maids Electrician 16 16 dash1
горничные Слесарь электрик 16 16 тире1
person
человек
Cool Interesting, it seems like you have
Прикольно Интересно у вас походу этих
more of these service personnel than
обслуживающего персонала больше чем
residents
проживающих
Well, at night I stay alone as the
Ну на ночь остаётся остаюсь я один как
duty administrator That's how it is People
дежурный администратор Вот так вот Люди
work but they do not work constantly
работают но они же не постоянно работают
but take turns Yes Yes But still, I
а сменяются Да Да Но всё равно я имею в
mean that it turns out that you have
виду что получается у вас обслуживающего
more service personnel than vacationers
персонала больше чем отдыхающих
Well, in the winter and in the summer In the summer,
Ну в зимний период да летом Летом вот
we have 100% occupancy for the summer
стопроцентная загрузка на лето у нас
Cool Well, there are probably more people,
Прикольно Ну и людей больше наверное
more workers Well, the
рабочих больше
thing is that in the summer
Ну дело в том что летом ещё открываются
additional buildings are opened on the sea and
дополнительные корпуса которые на море а
there are already
там уже идут и
restaurants I see Here And how much is your
рестораны Понятно Вот И сколько у тебя
salary
зарплата
I can't tell you about that, well, what is the
я не могу вам говорить о том ну по какой
order of salaries in Saki
порядок зарплат в саках
depending on what people
в зависимости от того чем люди
do There are people who work for
занимаются Есть люди которые работают на
20,000 they are happy There are people who
20.000 они счастливы Есть люди которые
work for 60,000 they are happy Yes There is one
работают за 60.000 они счастливы Да Есть
who lives in the trash and he is happy I did
который живёт на мусорке и он счастлив Я
n't ask about happiness, I asked:
же спросил не про счастье а я спросил:
"How much do people earn in Saki?"
"Сколько зарабатывают люди в саках?"
Well, around 40,000 rubles.
Ну в районе 40.000 руб
This is not in the resort season, in winter.
Это в курортный сезон нет зимой
Ordinary workers in winter
Обычные работяги зимой
400 dollars, in short, about that. Yes,
400 долларов короче около того да
that is, it turns out that gasoline is here for
то есть получается бензин у нас по
gasoline, yes, what difference does it make how much
бензин у нас да какая разница сколько
gasoline is, uh, if a person gets 400
бензин ээ если человек получает 400
dollars, how much gasoline is this?
долларов вообще сколько бензин это
Poverty. Yes, let's say so. Well, people
Бедность да пусть будет так Ну люди
live better than they did under
живут всё всяко лучше чем было при
Ukraine, you know. Yes, that's good. Even I'm
Украине понимаете да Ну это хорошо Даже
happy for you. Really, that's
я счастлив за вас Действительно
great. Thank you for that. Well, let's say so.
это здорово Спасибо вам за такое Ну в
I'll say more than that. Yes, I
скажем так я больше того скажу да я
recently thought. Yes, for example,
недавно думал да вот например вот такие
guys like you who live there in Crimea
ребята как вы которые живут там в Крыму
and live better than under Ukraine, I'm
и лучше живут чем при Украине я счастлив
really happy for them. Thank you.
за них реально Спасибо
Yes. Can you tell me how bad it
Да А можешь рассказать как тебе плохо
was for you under Ukraine?
было при Украине
Well, I remember the times when my father was
ну я помню времена когда отцу зарплату
not given a salary, although he was in the military. Listen,
не давали хотя он был военно Слушай
how old are you?
сколько тебе лет
I'm 28. 28. I understand. That is, you were 18 when it was
мне 28 28 понял То есть тебе было 18 при
adopted.
утвоении
Yes. Tell me how bad your life was.
да Да Расскажи как тебе плохо жилось да
Yes, Oh, what should I tell you? You
Ой а что же мне вам рассказывать вы же
know everything perfectly well. No, don't tell me.
сами всё прекрасно знаете Не не расскажи
I want to be the first to hear. I'm not
Я хочу из первых устшать
interested in talking about this. And
Мне неинтересно об этом общаться А
why did something happen?
почему что случилось алло
Hello. Well, can you tell me how bad it was for you?  you can go online and read all this
Ну вы можете зайти в интернет и всё это
I'm not there on the Internet they
прочитать Я не там в интернете всякое
can write all sorts of things You are a real person who
могут писать Ты реально человек который
lives in Saka who really knows
живёт в Сака который действительно знает
that he lives better now than under Ukraine
что сейчас живёт лучше чем при Украине
Tell me how bad it was to live under Ukraine Don't get
Расскажи как плохо жилось при Украине Не
nervous with your hands Don't click Don't get nervous Be nervous And
нервничай руками Не щёлкай Не нервничай
I'm nervous I Yes-yes Yes You
Нервничай А я нервничаю Я Дадада Да
click this Yes Yes Well look when I
Щёлкаешь этим Да Да Ну смотрите я когда
went to
поступал
study ah-ah I studied at a university I
учиться а-а я учился в вузе у меня
had a scholarship You've started clicking your pen now
стипендия была Ты теперь начал ручкой
Yes I'm a nervous person in general I'm nervous
Да я нервный человек вообще Нервничаю
nervous Look I had a scholarship
нервничаю Смотрите у меня была стипендия
I had a scholarship of 250
У меня была стипендия 250
hryvnia Do you think this is normal well the
гривен Как вы считаете это нормальная ну
salary amount people had at that
сумма зарплаты у людей были по на тот
time for the middle management was 1,800 hryvnia Yeah
момент у среднего звена 1.800 гривен Угу
Scholarship Let's do it this way Scholarship
Стипендия Давайте так Стипендия
Scholarship - it was 30 dollars it
Стипендия - это было 30 долларов
turns out Cool And how much is the
получается Прикольно А сколько сейчас
scholarship in Russia now I don't know I And yes-yes How much How much is the
стипендия в России я не знаю я А да-дада
scholarship in
Сколько Сколько сейчас стипендия в
Russia now  but then when
России но потом когда
And now I'll tell you now now the
А сейчас я тебе скажу сейчас сейчас
scholarship in Russia is 2,000 rubles That's 20
стипендия в России 2.000 руб Это 20
dollars less than it was in Ukraine
долларов меньше чем в Украине было
Maybe I don't know Where did you get this
Может быть я не знаю Откуда вы взяли эту
information that and I talked I talked with
информацию что а я общался я общался со
students from Russia I immediately ask a
студентами из России Я сразу задаю
question about the scholarship Yes, come on I understand And did you
вопрос о стипендии Да давай Я понял А вы
talk to people who
общались с людьми которые на кого
studied for what who are studying now What are they
учились которые сейчас учатся На кого
studying for different different specialties There are
учатся разные разные специальности Есть
doctors there are all the same yes from 1.00 to 21
медики есть всех однапя да от 1.00 до 21
fluctuates depending on the region Can
колеблется в зависимости от региона
you imagine what dust so-so Well,
Представляете какая пыль тактак Ну
tell me further how bad it was to live under
рассказывай дальше как плохо жилось при
Ukraine And look, here's where I
Украине А смотрите вот на чём я
stopped and about the salary yes for the middle
остановился а на зарплате да у среднего
management for people who, for example,
звена у людей вот которые допустим
worked in sanatoriums service
работали в санаториях обслуживающие
personnel such as waiters cooks
персонал такие как официанты повара у
their salary was 1,800 dash 2,400 in
них зарплата была 1.800 тире 2400 в
hryvnia
гривнах
How much how much
Сколько сколько
1,800 dash 2,400 in hryvnia Then I remember
1.800 тире 2400 в гривнах Тогда я помню
how much my mother
как сколько моя мать пола 300 долларов
received like 300 dollars uh You want to say that  The
типа получал ээ Ты хочешь сказать что
waiter got 300 dollars and how are
300 долларов получал официант а вы како
you And how are you, uncle, I'm sick of you
вы А как дядька надоел ты мне
Complete
Полное
destruction
уничтожение
was This is divine and they just promoted it
было Это божественно да раскрутили это
People for this like, subscribe and
просто Народ за это лайк підписка и
comment Need to spread to everyone you know so they can
комент Треба розкинути всім знайомим щоб
laugh at this
посміялись це
Subscribe to my Instagram I don't
було Підпишись на мій Instagram я не
know why you do this why else would I
знаю для чго це тобі для чого ще тобі
look at you on Face But for you it's one,
там дивитись на Face Але для тебе це оди
two or three clicks but you support me
два або три клика але ти підтримаєш мене
and I'll say: "Wow, I have a bunch of
и я буду казати: "Уау в мене там купа
followers and I'll be in a great mood"
фоловерів и в мене буде класний настро"
Subscribe to Instagram Popik Andrey That's it
Подпишись на Instagram Попик Андрей Вот
Chick-chick-chick Let me give you a hard time
так Чик-чик-чикчик Давай я тебя очкаю